<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title><![CDATA[Gatsby Starter Blog RSS Feed]]></title><description><![CDATA[Cyber Security concepts, tools  news and more.]]></description><link>https://pegromdev.github.io/pegromdev</link><generator>GatsbyJS</generator><lastBuildDate>Fri, 25 Nov 2022 07:35:31 GMT</lastBuildDate><item><title><![CDATA[What is Cybersecurity]]></title><description><![CDATA[When you think about security things like protection and prevention comes to mind for sure so if Cyber is the case we are talking about the…]]></description><link>https://pegromdev.github.io/pegromdev/whatIsCybersecurity/whatIsCybersecurity/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://pegromdev.github.io/pegromdev/whatIsCybersecurity/whatIsCybersecurity/</guid><pubDate>Fri, 25 Nov 2022 22:12:03 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;When you think about security things like protection and prevention comes to mind for sure so if Cyber is the case we are talking about the protection of computers, information and all the digital content you could imagine; so basically at its core it means data protection; the process and standards are to complex to resume but the key concept to understand is that what is all about is SECURING DATA! So to me Cyber Security means the process of Securing Data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;What is data?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The whole point of the web is to transfer Data isn&apos;t?... Hackers want them and company&apos;s sell them and so on but what is it?;
well yes, you already know, text,audio,video etc; and when translated to computer language we also understand how that end up don&apos;t we?;
maybe 1&apos;s and 0&apos;s as always in a binary system I guess, Positive and Negative, Black and White and you know what I am gonna said next As Above So Below...
In the end those pretty Disk Drives are so valuable that I think that now you might start to pay attention because after all is your data Secure?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;How Secure is your data?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let&apos;s see, if Cyber security is the process of securing data it might sound already like insecurity may be around the block or what?
Imagine you own an USB drive with a text file that says hello, and you keep that Thumb drive in a safe box, is that secure? Because it looks like it is but here comes another question
for how long? And I am not saying that someone might brake in, I am saying that data storage devices also have a life spawn and yes it might end up being unrecoverable!.
Do you own copies of your data?, is your data encrypted?, is it accessible thru the web? I mean do you even know how much data you have?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;The process of securing data&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So now you thinking Cyber Security make sense don&apos;t you?;safeguarding important data from corruption, compromise or loss is the  process of securing data and it depends of many different things like the operating system that interacts with the information because it might have methods and ways of doing things that may not apply to others operating systems, so it all depends on what data and where is the data store!, is key to understand that securing data means the capability of restoring in case that gets inaccessible or unusable, protected data also should be available when needed and usable for its intended purpose, meaning under authorize rights and so on... You can see how we are getting deeper now...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Getting Deeper&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From some of the world leaders: &quot;cyber risk is the greatest risk facing our economy.&quot; Or not but is definitely changing it!.. You might want to take a deeper look specially at digital privacy and the whole yards.... Here we start our journey basically pointing out that digital data is how we run things and yes it needs to be secure because is not. I am sure you will learn to protect yours and help others do as well. I am not detailing farther because there is a lot to go thru so lets move on.
In the most humble way lets start by taking a look at files more deeply and how its processed by operating systems or more exactly by Linux machines shall we?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;&quot;&gt;Files and formats!&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;strong&gt;Comming Soon!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Who I am]]></title><description><![CDATA[My name is Nicolas also know as pegrom or some call me a nerd or a geek depending on the subject..
People see my self as a very technical…]]></description><link>https://pegromdev.github.io/pegromdev/whoIam/whoIam/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://pegromdev.github.io/pegromdev/whoIam/whoIam/</guid><pubDate>Thu, 24 Nov 2022 22:12:03 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;My name is Nicolas also know as pegrom or some call me a nerd or a geek depending on the subject..
People see my self as a very technical oriented person, because you are what people see and think of you or are you not? JUST KIDDING!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 1995  thanks to a Friend who paid for me I sing up for computer classes to learn windows 95 and it was one of  those moments where you know passion is in you, then in 2002 I meet Linux, more exactly Red hat Linux and hey I fell in love for it... I won&apos;t go into anymore details because what I am trying to convey is that I been around for long and I know that I gonna be around for a while more... So lets discuss why I am here now shall we?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am here to talk about Cyber Security for a few reasons like reinforce some knowledge, share and discuss basics tools and practices and most importantly practicing writing skills are just a few... The goal is to bring awareness and motivation on how to secure things, where to start or share about how i am planing to brake in the Cyber Security Field to those who are interested as I am.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item></channel></rss>