<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title><![CDATA[Gatsby Starter Blog RSS Feed]]></title><description><![CDATA[Cyber Security concepts, tools  news and more.]]></description><link>https://pegromdev.github.io/pegromdev</link><generator>GatsbyJS</generator><lastBuildDate>Fri, 25 Nov 2022 04:08:56 GMT</lastBuildDate><item><title><![CDATA[Who I am]]></title><description><![CDATA[My name is Nicolas also know as pegrom or some call me a nerd or a geek depending on the subject..
People see my self as a very technical…]]></description><link>https://pegromdev.github.io/pegromdev/whoIam/whoIam/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://pegromdev.github.io/pegromdev/whoIam/whoIam/</guid><pubDate>Thu, 24 Nov 2022 22:12:03 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;My name is Nicolas also know as pegrom or some call me a nerd or a geek depending on the subject..
People see my self as a very technical oriented person, because you are what people see and think of you or are you not? JUST KIDDING!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 1995  thanks to a Friend who paid for me I sing up for computer classes to learn windows 95 and it was one of  those moments where you know passion is in you, then in 2002 I meet Linux, more exactly Red hat Linux and hey I fell in love for it... I won&apos;t go into anymore details because what I am trying to convey is that I been around for long and I know that I gonna be around for a while more... So lets discuss why I am here now shall we?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am here to talk about Cyber Security for a few reasons like reinforce some knowledge, share and discuss basics tools and practices and most importantly practicing writing skills are just a few... The goal is to bring awareness and motivation on how to secure things, where to start or share about how i am planing to brake in the Cyber Security Field to those who are interested as I am.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item></channel></rss>